<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jamesphare.org</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on jamesphare.org</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a researcher, project manager, writer, and editor living in Decatur, Georgia. Recently, I have been focused on improving my data science skills, including statistical analysis and programming in R. Follow along with my progress on my blog.
Prior to moving to Georgia, I spent five years as a project manager at the Rosa Luxemburg Stiftung’s New York office. RLS is a democratic socialist political education foundation closely affiliated with Germany’s Left Party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>My academic research explored the development of modern Hinduism in colonial and pre-colonial South Asia. I was awarded a PhD in Religion by Columbia University in 2011. I still hope to revise my dissertation for publication. My dissertation focuses on Nābhādās’ Bhaktamāl (Garland of Devotees). This late sixteenth- or early seventeenth-century collection of hagiographies praises the qualities of hundreds of devotees and thereby sets the boundaries of a devotional community far exceeding the sectarian context of its author.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing &amp; Editing</title>
      <link>/writing-editing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/writing-editing/</guid>
      <description>Selected Publications “Strategies Against the Far Right: Reporting Back and Moving Forward,” Rosa Luxemburg Stiftung–New York Office, August 2017.title: Writing &amp;amp; Editing
“Paris Is Burning,” Rosa Luxemburg Stiftung–New York Office, June 2017. Also available in German translation. Reprinted in Neues Deutschland, Portside, The Bullet, and [ZNet](https://zcomm.org/znetarticle/paris-is-burning/.
“Mapping Socialist Strategies: Reporting Back and Moving Forward,” Rosa Luxemburg Stiftung–New York Office, September 2014.
“Steal the Vote: Voter Suppression in the Twenty-first Century,” Rosa Luxemburg Stiftung–New York Office, October 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extinct Plants</title>
      <link>/2020/08/18/extinct-plants/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/08/18/extinct-plants/</guid>
      <description>For this week’s Tidy Tuesday, I’m exploring data from the International Union for Conservation of Nature on extinct plants, including both species which are totally extinct and those which survive only under cultivation.
As I explored the data on these 500 species (see my notes), a handful of stories leaped out at me that I thought could best be communicated through simple, bold graphics. The first is how much plant extinction has taken place in Africa and in Madagascar in particular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systemic Racism in the NYPD</title>
      <link>/2020/07/28/systemic-racism-in-the-nypd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/28/systemic-racism-in-the-nypd/</guid>
      <description>ProPublica recently released a partial database of New York Police Department (NYPD) disciplinary records. An analysis of substantiated complaints of police misconduct reveals clear systemic racism. Black people face wildly disproportionate amounts of police misconduct regardless of the race or gender of individual officers.
Following a change to the New York law that kept police officers’ disciplinary records secret—and amid an ongoing lawsuit—ProPublica has released a searchable database of complaints to the Civilian Complaint Review Board (CCRB).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter</title>
      <link>/2020/07/26/twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/26/twitter/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been exploring my personal Twitter data using the Twitter API (with the rtweet package) and the tidytext text-mining package. I haven’t come up with any mind-blowing conclusions but it’s been fun to see who my favorite tweeters are, who their favorite tweeters are, what we tweet about, and how the sentiment of my tweets has changed over time. I did not like it when Bernie Sanders dropped out of the presidential race or when Brian Kemp reopened Georgia’s economy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Astronauts</title>
      <link>/2020/07/14/tidy-astronauts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/14/tidy-astronauts/</guid>
      <description>As part of the TidyTuesday project, I created this visualization of who has gone into space based on gender and nationality. This is my first attempt at mapping data geographically! I’m pretty pleased with how it turned out, but I would welcome any feedback. The code is available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 in DeKalb County, Georgia</title>
      <link>/2020/07/10/covid-19-in-dekalb-county-georgia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/10/covid-19-in-dekalb-county-georgia/</guid>
      <description>So this post may be something of a cautionary tale about getting ahead of yourself when it comes to analyzing data. The DeKalb County Board of Health releases numbers on the spread of COVID-19 in the county, most recently on July 6. Included with these data is a breakdown of the county’s 7,043 cases by ZIP Code. It is immediately apparent that while this disease has affected the entire county, its effects have not been felt evenly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Predictor</title>
      <link>/2020/06/24/running-predictor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/24/running-predictor/</guid>
      <description>The Model I have been recording my runs in Strava for about five years. I wanted to see if I could use this data to make predictions about my racing pace. I downloaded my data from the website, including a spreadsheet collecting all my activity data (I’ve deleted some data from this file for privacy reasons).
I spent some time using visualizations and linear models to determine which variables would provide the most predictive power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 in Metro Atlanta</title>
      <link>/2020/06/21/covid-19-in-metro-atlanta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/21/covid-19-in-metro-atlanta/</guid>
      <description>Early on in the pandemic, I became frustrated by the lack of quality visualizations of local COVID-19 data, particularly concerning Metro Atlanta, where I live, so I set out to create a set of visualizations of these data. Since then, the situation has improved greatly, but these plots still provide some details and comparisons that I have not seen elsewhere.
The first item I set out to create is an Rmarkdown document focused on Metro Atlanta that visualizes the distribution of cases and deaths as they change over time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>